Louis A. Witzeman Collection of Rural/Metro Corporation Records, 1947-2004
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Louis A. Witzeman Collection of Rural/Metro Corporation Records 1947-2004
MS 400
Rural/Metro Corporation
Records, 1947-2004. This collection includes business files; company history materials; materials regarding Rural/Metro founder Louis A. Witzeman; correspondence; photographs, negatives, and slides (featuring images of fire fighting, fire damage, fire hazards, fire engines, personnel, stations, and equipment); photocopies of scrapbooks and news clippings; audiovisual materials; and memorabilia.
12 linear feet (Approximately 15,000 items).
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Rural/Metro Corporation began in 1948 as the Rural Fire Protection Company-a privately-run subscription fire service serving the unincorporated area north of Phoenix, Arizona. Louis A. Witzeman founded the company after watching a neighbor's home burn unchecked because there was no fire protection available in the unincorporated area where the home was located. In 1951, the Rural Fire Protection Company contracted to provide fire protection for the newly-incorporated city of Scottsdale, Arizona. Rural Fire Protection Company changed the name of its fire fighting operations to Rural/Metro Fire Department after purchasing Phoenix's Metropolitan Fire Department in 1960. Over the years the company expanded its activities significantly to include provision of fire protection for several Arizona cities as well as for cities in several other states. Additionally, the company expanded its range of operations to include ambulance service, security patrol service, hazardous materials response service, and emergency services consulting. The company changed its name to Rural/Metro Corporation in 1972. Witzeman retired from Rural/Metro in 1978 and sold the company to his employees through an employee stock ownership plan.
Organization
This collection is organized into eleven series. Two series contain subseries: Business Files and Photographs.
Series 1: Business Files, 1947-2004
Subseries: Accounting and Finance, 1947-2004
Subseries: Contracts, 1947-1984
Subseries: Legal, 1947-1984
Subseries: Real Estate, 1951-1983
Subseries: Reports, 1961-2003
Subseries: Sales, Marketing, and Advertising, 1948-2002
Subseries: Speeches, 1969-1996
Series 2: Company History, 1966-2002
Series 3: Louis A. Witzeman, 1966-2004
Series 4: Correspondence, 1949-2004
Series 5: Photographs, 1948-1993
Subseries: Community Outreach, 1963-1972
Subseries: Equipment, 1963-1973
Subseries: Fire Engines, 1950-1979
Subseries: Fire Hazards, undated
Subseries: Fire stations, 1950-1975
Subseries: Fires, 1948-1990
Subseries: Publicity, 1950-1993
Series 6: Negatives and Slides, 1950-1982
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1948-1986
Series 8: News Clippings, 1948-2004
Series 9: Audiovisual, 1969-2001
Series 10: Memorabilia, 1976-1988
Series 11: Oversized Materials (contains memorabilia, photographs, and one scrapbook)
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes business files; company history materials; materials regarding Rural/Metro founder Louis A. Witzeman; correspondence; photographs, negatives, and slides (featuring images of fire fighting, fire damage, fire hazards, fire engines, personnel, stations, and equipment); photocopies of scrapbooks and news clippings; audiovisual materials; and memorabilia. Rural/Metro Corporation often received national publicity, particularly regarding the privatization of fire protection which traditionally had been a public sector service. Articles appeared in major publications such as Newsweek, U.S. News and World Report, Reader's Digest, Wall Street Journal, New York Times, and Los Angeles Times. These articles, as well as many others, are included in the collection. Additionally, Rural/Metro was featured on the television programs "60 Minutes" (1978) and "Good Morning America" (2000). While the "60 Minutes" broadcast is not in the collection, a Scottsdale Quarterly magazine article describing it is included in the collection. Also, the Rural/Metro History Project (located in Series 2: Company History) contains a brief description of the broadcast. The "Good Morning America" broadcast (on VHS) is included in the collection in the audiovisual series
Witzeman, Louis A., 1924-2004; Rural/Metro Corporation--Records and Correspondence; Elections--Scottsdale,Arizona--2003; Fire Chiefs; Fire Departments; Fire Departments--Equipment and Supplies; Fire Departments--Officials and Employees; Fire Departments--Southwest; Fire Departments--Maricopa County, Arizona; Fire Departments--Pima County, Arizona; Fire Engines; Fire Fighters; Fire Fighters--Labor Unions; Fire Hose; Hydrants; Fire Prevention; Fire Protection Districts; Fire Sprinklers; Fire Stations; Mayors--Scottsdale, Arizona--Drinkwater, Herb, d. 1997; Drinkwater, Herb, d. 1997--Mayor--Scottsdale, Arizona; Privatization; Phoenix Fire Department; Scottsdale Fire Department; Tucson Fire Department
Container List
- Series 1: Business Files, 1947-2004
  3.5 linear feet (Approximately 5,250 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical
  The Business Files Series is divided into seven subseries. Accounting and Finance (1947-1987), contains some balance sheets, bank documents, and board of directors meeting minutes. Contracts (1947-1984), contains copies of various fire protection and security patrol contracts made with cities, homeowners associations, and individuals. Legal (1947-1984), mainly contains legal materials pertaining to dealings with the Arizona Corporation Commission. Real Estate (1951-1983), contains documents concerning the company's property holdings. Reports (1961-2003), contains Rural/Metro Corporation and Scottsdale Fire Department annual reports, as well as other reports. Sales, Marketing, and Advertising (1948-2002), contains advertisements, brochures, and press books. Speeches (1969-1996), contains Louis A. Witzeman's speeches, including drafts, final versions, and published versions that he delivered to various fire fighting and privatization-related organizations.
  - Subseries: Accounting and Finance. 1947-1987
    - Balance Sheets for AAA Fire Equipment Company. 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Balance Sheets for Rural Fire Protection Company. 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Balance Sheets for Rural Fire Protection Company. 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bank Documents. 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bank Documents. 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bank Documents. 1960-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes. 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes. 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes. 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Financial Growth Charts. 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Invoices. 1947-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Stock Certificates. 1948-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Stock Evaluation. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Subseries: Contracts 1947-1987
    - Bank of Douglas, Arizona Escrow Contract. 1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Carondelet Health Services Contract. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Homeowner Fire Contracts. 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Mark Realty Development Contract. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Sabino Vista Volunteer Fire District Contract. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community Fire Contract. 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - San Luis Fire Contract. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Scottsdale Fire Contract. 1951-1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Sandpiper Scottsdale Homeowners Association Security Patrol Contract. 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Scottsdale Memorial Hospital Contract. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Sun City Volunteer Fire District Contract. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Sun City West Fire District Contract. 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sun Tree Homeowners Association Security Patrol Contract. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Tolleson Fire Contract Addendum. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Tucson Estates Fire District Contract. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Tucson General Hospital Contract. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Union Oil Company Microwave Telecommunications Contract. 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Woodland Springs Homeowners Association Security Patrol Contract. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Legal, 1947-1984
    - Arizona Corporation Commission. 1947-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Arizona Revised Statutes Private Ambulance Insurance Exemption (Draft). undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Scottsdale Sprinkler Ordinance. 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Subseries: Real Estate. 1951-1983
    - Property Lists and Appraisal Reports. 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Title Insurance Policy. 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Subseries: Reports. 1961-2003
    - Adam Smith Institute, Re-Servicing Britain. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bay Village, Ohio, Ohio Inspection Bureau Report. 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Dade County Fire Department, Emergency Medical Rescue Frequency of Alarms Reported. 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - CEMA, Private Sector Fire Protection. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Falck & Zonen, Falck & Zonen in Denmark. undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - FEMA, Indirect Costs of Residential Fires. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - FEMA, Uniform Design for a Computer-Aided Dispatch System. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Goldwater Institute, Policy Report RE: Rural/Metro. 2003 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Independent Cities of Los Angeles County, Fire Service Fiddlers on the Roof. 1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Institute for Economic Research, Efficiency in the Provision of Fire Services. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Institute for Local Self-Government, Alternatives to Traditional Public Safety Delivery Systems. undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Institute for Local Self-Government, Modern Technology in Fire Service. 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Insurance Services Office, Grading Schedule for Municipal Fire Protection. 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Johns Hopkins University, Soviet Abstract Journal Section 68 Fire Protection. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Maricopa Association of Governments, Pima Road Study. 1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - National Association of State Foresters, Fire Protection in Rural America: A Challenge for the Future. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - National Bureau of Standards, Factors Affecting Innovation in Fire Services. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - National Fire Protection Association, Black Tiger Fire Case Study. undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - National Fire Protection Association, NFPA 25 Water-Based Fire Protection Systems. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - National Fire Protection Association, NFPA Standard on Firefighting Foam Chemicals. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - National Fire Protection Association, Operation Water. undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - National League of Cities, Grading of Municipal Fire Protection Facilities. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - National League of Cities, Municipal Fire Prevention Programs and Legislation. undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - PESA, Privatization: The Future of Emergency Services. undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Rural/Metro, Annual Report. 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Rural/Metro, Annual Report. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Rural/Metro, Annual Report. 1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Rural/Metro, Annual Report. 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Rural/Metro, Brief Study of Water Consumed in Firefighting in Five Areas. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Rural/Metro, Division 11 Yuma County/Pima County Operation Readiness Inspection Report (includes photographs). 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Rural/Metro, Employee Stock Ownership Plan. undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Rural/Metro, Harvard University Case Study on Rural/Metro. 1979-1996 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Rural/Metro, Managing Service Innovation: Rural/Metro Corporation Case Study. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Rural/Metro, Personnel Rules and Regulations. 1965-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Rural/Metro, Planning and Status for Maricopa County Service Areas. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Rural/Metro, Rebuttal to Flagstaff Fire Chief’s Fire Protection Analysis. undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Rural/Metro; Rye Brook, New York Fire Services. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale Annual Activities Report FY 1999-2000. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale Annual Activities Report FY 2000-2001. 2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale Annual Activities Report FY 2001-2002. 2002 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale Annual Activities Report FY 2002-2003. 2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report. undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1960. 1961 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1961. 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1963. 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1965-1966. 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1967-1968. 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1968-1969. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1969-1970. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1970-1971. 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1971-1972. 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1972-1973. 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1973-1974. 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1974-1975. 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1975-1976. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report 1976. 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1977-1978. 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1978-1979. 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Annual Report FY 1979-1980. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale F.D. Commentary on the Jimenez Report. 1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale Life Safety Ordinance (1 of 2). undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale Life Safety Ordinance (2 of 2). undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Rural/Metro, Scottsdale Memorial Hospital Fire Brigade Class. 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Rural/Metro; The Snail, Truck 21, and Hydrant Opening Device. 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Rural/Metro, Sprinkler Study and Model Ordinance. undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Rural/Metro, Structural Firefighting Water Use Study. 1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Rural/Metro, Tennessee Rural/Metro Progress Report. 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Tacoma Fire Department, Remote Hydrant Operator Acceptance Tests. 1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Tacoma, Washington; Fire Service Demand Charge Study. 1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Tacoma, Washington; Technology Transfer: The Case of the Automatic Hydrant Valve. 1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce, Fire Research Publications 1983. 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce, Impact of the Use of Smoke Detectors. 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Forest Service, Southwestern Region Fire Report. 1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Vanderbilt University, Research Proposal Submitted to National Science Foundation. 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Witzeman Center for Privatization, Privatization in Arizona’s Largest Cities. 1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Subseries: Sales, Marketing, and Advertising. 1948-2002
    - Advertisements. undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Advertisements. 1948-1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Brochures. undated (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Brochures. 1955-2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Press Book. undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Press Book. 1978 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Subseries: Speeches. 1969-1996
    - General (1 of 3). undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - General (2 of 3). undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - General (3 of 3). undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - General. 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - General. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - General. 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - General. 1983-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Company History. 1966-2002
  .75 linear feet (Approximately 1,125 items)
  The Company History Series contains material regarding company anniversaries (twenty-fifth, thirtieth, fortieth, and fiftieth), magazine articles, company newsletters, and items of historical significance such as early company postcards and stationery.
  - Anniversary—25th. 1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary—30th. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Anniversary—40th. 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary—50th. 1998 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Elk Lodge Certificate of Appreciation to Scottsdale F.D. 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - History Project (1 of 2). 1996 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - History Project (2 of 2). 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Magazine Articles. 1968-1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Magazine Articles. 1981-1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Magazine Articles. 1991-2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters. 1968-1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters. 1979-1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Organizational Charts. undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Pima County. 1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Post Cards. undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Scottsdale: Jewel in the Desert. 1984 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Stationery. undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Series 3: Louis A. Witzeman. 1966-2004
  .25 linear feet (Approximately 375 items)
  This series concerns Louis A. Witzeman, Rural/Metro founder and long-time company president. Contains material regarding honors bestowed on Witzeman (Arizona Fire Service Hall of Fame, Scottsdale Hall of Fame, the National Fire Protection Association Research Foundation Medal), Witzeman’s 1972 European trip, Witzeman’s 1981 retirement party, Witzeman’s autobiography, and tributes published upon Witzeman’s death in 2004.
  - Arizona Fire Service Hall of Fame. 2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - European Trip. 1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - General. 1966-2004 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - National Fire Protection Association Research Foundation Medal. 2001 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rebel in Retrospect (Autobiography). 2004 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Retirement. 1981 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Scottsdale Hall of Fame. 1994-2003 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Series 4: Correspondence, 1949-2004
  .5 linear feet (Approximately 750 items)
  The bulk of the Correspondence Series is composed of general correspondence. The series also contains subject-related correspondence regarding such subjects as Scottsdale Mayor Herb Drinkwater, Mark Frazier (Director of the Local Government Center, the Taxpayer’s Foundation, and the Sabre Foundation), Station Orders, the Witzeman Center for Privatization, and the intensely-campaigned 2003 Scottsdale Election where Scottsdale citizens voted to retain the private fire protection services of Rural/Metro rather than switch to a municipally-run fire department.
  - American Society of Local Officials. 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Business. 1949-1960 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Drinkwater, Herb. 1981-1997 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Frazier, Mark. 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - General. undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - General. 1949-1955 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - General. 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - General. 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - General. 1980-1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - General. 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - General. 1992-1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - General. 2001-2004 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Scottsdale Election. 2001-2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Scottsdale Election. 2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series 5: Photographs, 1948-1993
  2.5 linear feet (Approximately 3,750 items)
  The Photographs Series is divided into eight subseries. Community Outreach (1963-1972), includes photographs of fire fighters visiting elementary schools, as well as team photographs of little league baseball teams sponsored by Rural/Metro. Equipment (1963-1973), contains photographs of basic equipment used by Rural/Metro fire fighters as well as technical innovations developed by Rural/Metro such as the “snail” and the “water tank” (remote-controlled fire fighting machines). Fire Engines (1950-1979), contains photographs of various fire engines, as well as some photographs of “plain janes”—new trucks with stripped down chassis assembled into full-fledged fire engines by Rural/Metro employees. Fire Hazards (undated), contains photographs of hazards such as piles of cardboard boxes and leaking chemical drums. Fire Stations (1950-1975), contains photographs of various stations as well as photographs of potential Paradise Valley Station sites. Fires (1948-1990), contains photographs of brush and hay fires, commercial and residential property fires, and vehicular fires. Miscellaneous (undated), contains miscellaneous photographs, including photographs of employees in the main office. Publicity (1950-1993), contains photographs of Fire Chief Robertson, Louis A. Witzeman, training exercises, and the Scottsdale Station groundbreaking. [Note: Additional oversized photographs are located in Series 11: Oversized Materials].
  - Subseries: Community Outreach. 1963-1972
    - General. undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Little League. 1963-1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Equipment. 1963-1973
    - Communication Devices, Protective Clothing, and Rescue Equipment. undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Communication Devices, Protective Clothing, and Rescue Equipment. 1963-1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Hydrants, the “Snail,” and the “Water Tank.” undated (Box 12, Folder 12-13)
    - Hydrants, the “Snail,” and the “Water Tank.” 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Pumps and Hoses. undated. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Pumps and Hoses. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries: Fire Engines. 1950-1979
    - Central Yavapai F.D. 1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Chautauqua, NY. 1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Clifton F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Edmonds F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Fairfield F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Hawthorne, Nevada F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Hermosillo, Mexico F.D. 1964-1966 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Horseshoe Bend F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Kaibeto-Shonto F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Myers Flat F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - NASA F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Oracle F.D. 1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Phoenix F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Pine-Strawberry F.D. undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - "Plain Janes." undated (Box 13, Folder 17-18)
    - "Plain Janes." 1971 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Rural/Metro. undated (Box 13, Folder 20-22)
    - Rural/Metro. 1950-1979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Show Low F.D. 1966 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sparks F.D. undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tatum F.D. undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified. undated (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - Unidentified. 1965-1974 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Wilson F.D. undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Subseries: Fire Hazards. undated
    - General. undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Fire Stations. 1950-1975
    - Apache Trail. undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Apache Trail. 1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Bisbee. 1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Cashion. undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Oracle. 1969 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Redningskorpsets. undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Rural/Metro. undated (Box 14, Folder 16-19)
    - Scottsdale. undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Scottsdale. 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Thomas and 29th. 1950 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Tucson. undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Tucson. 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)